[{"question":"# Q1. A dataset that includes \\_ can be used to create a map visualization. (Select all that apply.)","options":["    A. house numbers, street names","    B. geospatial data","    C. city names, country names","    D. longitude, latitude"," A, B, C, D"," A, C, D"," B, C, D"," D"],"anwserIndex":4,"answerText":" A, B, C, D"},{"question":"# Q2. How do you create a chart visual in Power Bl Desktop Report view? (Select all that apply.)","options":["    A. Click New Visual on the Home tab.","    B. Select a chart visual in the Visualizations pane.","    C. Click New Visual on the Data Tools tab.","    D. Select a field that contains values."," A, B, or D"," B or D"," B orC"," A or B"],"anwserIndex":7,"answerText":" A or B"},{"question":"# Q3. What daily sales number does this DAX measure formula calculate? ","options":["CALCULATE(SUM([Sales]) ,DATESHTD([Date] ))"," running total sales in each month that starts over each month"," total sales for the entire month"," running total in entire year for the entire month"," rolling average over 12 months of sales"],"anwserIndex":3,"answerText":" running total in entire year for the entire month"},{"question":"# Q4. You are creating a report in Power Bl Desktop and want to restrict the data to records where Country=\"Canada\". To accomplish this, what do you need to create?","options":[" a directive"," a custom column"," an indexed column"," a parameter"],"anwserIndex":0,"answerText":" a directive"},{"question":"# Q5. What is the primary benefit of using visualizations such as line charts, bar charts, and column charts?","options":[" They are easier to create than other visualizations."," They require fewer resources than more complex visualizations."," They are also used in Excel, so they feel familiar to users."," They are free to use."],"anwserIndex":1,"answerText":" They require fewer resources than more complex visualizations."},{"question":"# Q6. In Power Bl service, deleted pages are available after deletion until","options":[" midnight of the day on which they are deleted"," the next billing cycle"," you empty the Recycle Bin"," the report has been saved"],"anwserIndex":3,"answerText":" the report has been saved"},{"question":"# Q7. You need to add a required color to a bar chart. How can you add an exact color value to an existing bar chart?","options":[" Click the color in the visual (e.g., the bars) and right-click to select the color."," You cannot select custom colors in a bar chart or related visual."," Select the value closest to this color from the color formatting options."," Enter the hex value into the color formatting options."],"anwserIndex":0,"answerText":" Click the color in the visual (e.g., the bars) and right-click to select the color."},{"question":"# Q8. The Excel function IF is nearly the same as which DAX function?","options":[" SWITCH"," IF"," IFX"," IFS"],"anwserIndex":2,"answerText":" IFX"},{"question":"# Q9. Consider the Power Bl extract, transform, and load process (ETL). During this process, data is read and then","options":[" stored in S"],"anwserIndex":0,"answerText":" stored in S"},{"question":"# QL Server","options":[" written to an OLAP cube"," assigned a data type"," sorted by primary key"]},{"question":"# Q10. Power Bl's Publish to Web option allows you to embed visualizations within \\_. (Select all that apply.)","options":["    A. blog posts","    B. email messages","    C. web sites","    D. text messages"," A,C"," C"," A, B, C"," A, B, C, D"],"anwserIndex":7,"answerText":" A, B, C, D"},{"question":"# Q11. What can you do within the Power Bl Desktop ","options":[]},{"question":"# Query Settings pane? (Select all that apply.)","options":["    A. Rename a query step.","    B. Delete a query step.","    C. Delete from one query step to the end.","    D. Reorder the steps."," B, C, D"," A, B, C, D [proof link](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/power-bi/transform-model/desktop-query-overview)"," A, B, D"," A, B, C"],"anwserIndex":5,"answerText":" A, B, C, D [proof link](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/power-bi/transform-model/desktop-query-overview)"},{"question":"# Q12. After you enter text in the ","options":[]},{"question":"# Q&A box or O&A visual, Power Bl will `\\_` your data to create a list of appropriate visualizations.","options":[" filter and group"," sort and filter"," sort, filter, and group"," sort and group"]},{"question":"# Q13. You just deleted a dashboard in the Power Bl service and want to get it back. What should you do?","options":[" Press Ctrl+Z. ","    [proof link1](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/power-bi/visuals/service-tips-and-tricks-for-color-formatting)","    [link2](https://www.edureka.co/community/26060/how-do-i-undo-something-in-power-bi)"," Select Undo from the toolbar."," You cannot undo the deletion of a dashboard."," Recover it from the Recycle Bin."],"anwserIndex":0,"answerText":" Press Ctrl+Z. "},{"question":"# Q14. You have a sales data source and want to relate the tables. The table that contains sales transactions is a _____ table that contains product information is a \\_ table .","options":[" dimension; fact"," lookup; data"," data; lookup"," data; supporting"]},{"question":"# Q15. When you are creating a formula in the Power Query Editor, what does IntelliSense provide a list of? (Select all that apply.)","options":["    A. columns","    B. tables","    C. functions","    D. data sources"," B,C"," A, C, D"," C,D"," A, B, C"]},{"question":"# Q16. You want to delete a dataset but the Power Bl service will not let you. What is the most likely cause?","options":[" A tile on your dashboard contains data from that dataset."," The dataset is already being used in a published app."," A report contains data from that dataset."," The dataset is in your workspace."],"anwserIndex":1,"answerText":" The dataset is already being used in a published app."},{"question":"# Q17. One of your data columns includes the city, state, and postal code line of a mailing address. You need to separate the fields so you can access the geospatial elements for a map visualization. What transformation should you apply?","options":[" Replace values"," Split column"," Modify data type"," Best fit geospatial"]},{"question":"# Q18. Formatting options within a visualization depend on what?","options":[" the visualization you are formatting ","   [proof link](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/power-bi/visuals/service-getting-started-with-color-formatting-and-axis-properties)"," the editor you use"," the visualization group"," your permissions"],"anwserIndex":0,"answerText":" the visualization you are formatting "},{"question":"# Q19. What tool can you use in Power Bl Desktop to reduce data?","options":[" report editor"," Power Query Editor"," dashboard"," data modeler"],"anwserIndex":3,"answerText":" data modeler"},{"question":"# Q20. What is NOT a valid data connection type for Power Bl Desktop?","options":[" Azure data"," file data"," relationships data"," database data"],"anwserIndex":2,"answerText":" relationships data"},{"question":"# Q21. Which data type can be uploaded directly to powerbi.com?","options":[" Excel files"," comma-separated value (CSV) files"," Power Bl Desktop files"," all of these answers"],"anwserIndex":3,"answerText":" all of these answers"},{"question":"# Q22. What does Power Bl Premium provide?","options":[" Power Bl Report Server"," report sharing without a per-user licens"," all of these answers"," dedicated capacity for your company"],"anwserIndex":2,"answerText":" all of these answers"},{"question":"# Q23. You have a report in Power Bl service and want to save the state of a report page for easy access. What feature helps you do this?","options":[" views"," filters"," bookmarks"," slicers"],"anwserIndex":0,"answerText":" views"},{"question":"# Q24. What daily sales number does this DAX measure formula calculate?","options":["CALCULATE(SUM([Sales]) ,DATESHTD([Date] ))"," running total sales in each month that starts over each month"," total sales for the entire month"," running total in entire year for the entire month"," rolling average over 12 months of sales"]},{"question":"# Q25.  What should you do to increase the readability of a report?","options":[" all of these answers"," Remove unnecessary field labels."," Select the most appropriate visualization."," Use borders."]},{"question":"# Q26. Which feature in the Power BI service is most useful when you need to create pages that present the same visualizations for different territories, salespeople, or teams?","options":[" landscape mode"," none of these answers"," Shrink to Fit"," templates "]},{"question":"# Q27. What should you use to highlight a specific visualization in a report? ","options":[" Spotlight"," Highlight "," Magnify "," None of the answers"]},{"question":"# Q28. What does My Workspace on powerbi.com include?  ","options":[" Visualizations and a fields list "," Toolbars and preferences "," Workbooks and visualizations "," Dashboards and reports "]},{"question":"# Q29. You want to access the underlying data for a specific data point in a visualization. What should you choose?","options":[" Drill up "," Drill down"," Expand to next level "," Collapse"]},{"question":"# Q30. You have a treemap visualization that groups by sales territory. To allow users to further analyze data for a specific territory, what filter should you apply?","options":[" Visual level"," Page level "," Drillthrough "," Expand down "]}]